Guide to the Stuart W. Leslie Oral histories on the Cold War and American Science
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stuart W. Leslie oral histories on the cold war and American science
1982-1991
SC0999
Leslie, Stuart W.
1 Linear feet (51 audiocassettes)
Collection contains 51 audiocassettes from interviews with Stanford faculty in physics, electrical engineering, aeronautics and material science, along with scientists and engineers at Bay Area companies, for his book: THE COLD WAR AND AMERICAN SCIENCE: THE MILITARY-INDUSTRIAL-ACADEMIC COMPLEX AT MIT AND STANFORD. Those interviewed include Marvin Chodorow, Edward Ginzton, Nicholas Hoff, Stanley F. Kaisel, Erwin Nalos, Martin Packard, William E. Perry, William Rambo, Ronald Smelt, Oswald Villard, and Walter Vincenti.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Stuart W. Leslie, 2010.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Alternative Formats
The collection has been digitized. Audiorecordings are available streaming online.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains 51 audiocassettes from interviews with Stanford faculty in physics, electrical engineering, aeronautics and material science, along with scientists and engineers at Bay Area companies, for his book: THE COLD WAR AND AMERICAN SCIENCE: THE MILITARY-INDUSTRIAL-ACADEMIC COMPLEX AT MIT AND STANFORD. Those interviewed include Marvin Chodorow, Edward Ginzton, Nicholas Hoff, Stanley F. Kaisel, Erwin Nalos, Martin Packard, William E. Perry, William Rambo, Ronald Smelt, Oswald Villard, and Walter Vincenti.
Access Terms
Chodorow, Marvin; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard), 1915-; Hoff, Nicholas J. (Nicholas John), 1906-; Kaisel, Stanley Francis.; Nalos, Erwin.; Packard, Martin E.; Perry, William E.; Rambo, William R. (William Ralph), 1916-; Smelt, Ronald.; Stuart, W. Leslie.; Villard, Oswald G.; Vincenti, Walter G., (Walter Guido), 1917-; Education, Higher--Political aspects--United States.; Military research--United States.
Collection Contents
- Sound recordings, 1 audiocassette(s)
  - Allis, William P., Jan. 20, 1988; 1.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ashley, Holt, July 28, 1987; 1.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bowler, Albert, undated; 1.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Brown, Herschel, Jun 24, 1991; 1.4-1.5; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bube, Richard H., Apr 5, 1989; 1.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Cannon, Robert, Jul 31, 1987; 1.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Chodorow, Marvin, 1982, 1984, 1989; 1.8-1.10; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - DeBra, Daniel B., June 28, 1991; 1.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Fire, Philip and Nelson Blackman, Aug 21, 1991; 1.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Frye, William E., June 26, 1991; 1.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Ginzton, Edward, Nov 26, 1984; 1.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Hibbard, Hall, Jun 20, 1991; 1.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Hoff, Nicholas, Jun 12 and Jul 30, 1987; 1.16-1.18; 3 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Huggins, Robert, Jul 30, 1987; 1.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Huntoon, Robert, Aug 10, 1987; 1.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Jenkins, Jobe, Jun 28, 1991; 1.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Kaisel, Stanley, Apr 6, 1989 and May 21, 1991; 1.22-1.23; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Kane, Ralph, Aug 9, 1982; 1.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - LaBerge, Walter B., Jun 21, 1991; 1.25-1.26; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Leifer, Meyer and Walter Sernvik, 1991 May 21; 1.27-1.28; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Linvill, John, Jun 13, 1988; 1.29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Lob, Chester, Aug 22, 1991; 1.30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Nalos, Erwin, Aug 26, 1991; 1.31-1.32; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Packard, Martin, Aug 10, 1982; 1.33; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Perry, William [E.], Aug 21, 1991; 1.34-1.35; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Pierce, John, May 21, 1991; 1.36; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Quesada, E. R., Jun 8-9, 1991; 1.37-1.38; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Rambo, William, Nov 27, 1984 and Jun 14, 1988; 1.39-1.40; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Smelt, Ronald, Aug 23, 1991; 1.41-1.42; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Steinberg, Morris, Jun 19, 1991; 1.43-1.44; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Sturrock, Peter, Jun 16, 1988; 1.45; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Van Dyke, Milton, Jun 16, 1988; 1.46; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Villard, Oswald, Nov 23, 1984 and Jun 13, 1988; 1.47-1.48; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Vincenti, Walter, Jun 9, 1987; 1.49-1.50; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Watkins, Dean, May 22, 1991; 1.51; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)